Finding aid for the Ronald F. Sigler papers LSC.2292
UCLA Library Special Collections
Ronald F. Sigler papers
1976-1990
UCLA Library Special Collections
Sigler, Ronald F., 1932-
Sigler, Ronald F.
Sigler, Lorraine
LSC.2292
1 linear feet (1 carton)
In 1981, Dr. Ronald Sigler was appointed to the Classifications and Rating Administration Board of the Motion Picture Association of America, the first librarian to serve on the board. The collection consists of film rating forms, clippings, memos, communications, information related to Richard Heffner, Chairmanof the Classification Ratings Administration.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Ron Sigler and Lorraine Sigler, 2015
General
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9981683153606533
Biographical/Historical note
Ronald Floyd Sigler was born in 1932 in Brooklyn, New York. He Earned a B.A. in music from Queens College (1956), Masters of Library Science from UCLA (1964), and Ph.D. in Library Science from Florida State University (1977); his Ph.D. dissertation concerned film censorship. From 1958 to 1964, he worked with the Buena Park Library District as the head of the Audio-Visual department, and was the Audio-Visual Coordinator for the County of Los Angeles Library system from 1965 to 1973. From 1975 to 1981, Sigler taught in the School of Library Science at the University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee. In 1977 he was asked to draft a Freedom to View Statement by the Education Film Library Association (EFLA) which was adopted by EFLA and the American Library Association. In 1981, Sigler was appointed to the Classification and Rating Administration (CARA) Board of the Motion Picture Association of America, the first librarian to serve on the board. CARA is responsible to issue ratings for motion pictures which are exhibited and distributed commercially in the United States.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of files related to Ronald Sigler's work with the Classification and Rating Administration (CARA) of the Motion Picture Association of America from circa 1981-1983. Included are rating forms, clippings, memos and communications, a small number of printed items about the rating system, and materials related to Richard Heffner, Chairman of CARA. The bulk of the ratings forms, clippings, memos and communications are photocopies.
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged in the following series:
Series 1. Film Rating Forms
Series 2. Richard Heffner
Series 3. Motion Picture Rating System Printed Material
Series 4. Memos and Communications
Series 5. Clippings and Articles
Metadata Rights Declaration
Finding aid description and metadata in this record are licensed under a Creative Commons Public Domain Designation (CC0 1.0 Universal). See LSC's Metadata Rights Statement for more information.
Motion pictures -- United States -- Evaluation -- Archives; Sigler, Ronald F.; Sigler, Lorraine
- Film Rating Forms, 1976-1982 (Box 1, Folder 1-8)
  Arrangement note
  The series is arranged alphabetically by film title.
  Scope and Contents note
  The series consists of photocopies of film rating forms representing a variety of motion pictures. Information on the forms mostly include: name of the rater, a brief summary of the film's content, rating, and justification. The forms were completed by Ronald Sigler and Albert Van Schmus.
  - Blank Rating Forms, (undated) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Rating Forms A-C, (1977, 1980-1982) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    With: Adolescent through Creep Show.
  - Ratings Forms D-G, (1980-1982) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    With: The Dark Crystal through The Guns and the Fury.
  - Ratings Forms for Fast Times, (1981-1982) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    With a small number of script pages and communication between Albert Van Schmus, MPAA Administrative Director, and Evelyn Rhine of Universal Pictures Law Department.
  - Ratings Forms H-L, (1976-1977, 1980-1982) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    With: Haircut, Halloween III, Hammett, Hands of Lightning, Harlan County, USA, Heartbreaker, Honky Tonk Man, Heart Like a Wheel, High Road to China, Head On, High Season, Homework, The Hunger, I Never Promised You a Rose Garden, Incubus, Independence Day, Inside Moves, It Came from Hollywood, Jekyll and Hyde...Together Again, Jimmy the Kid, Jinxed, Justice of the Dragon, Kiss Me Goodbye, Lady Chatterley's Lover, Lady on the Bus, The Last American Virgin, The Last Unicorn, Lianna, Little Orphan Annie, Lola, Lookin' to Get Out, and Love Child.
  - Ratings Forms M-Q, (1980-1982) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    With: The Man from Snowy River, Matisse Madness, Megaforce, Melody in Love, The Memoirs of a French Whore, Midnight, Midsummer Night's Sex Comedy, Missing, The Missionary, Monsignor, Montenegro, Monty Python Live at the Hollywood Bowl, Mother Lode, My Favorite Year, National Lampoon's Class Reunion, Night Crossing, Night Eyes, Night of the Shooting Stars, Night Shift, The Night of the Shooting Stars, Nighthawks, Nightmare, Norma Rae, Norman Loves Rose, Officer and a Gentleman, One Day at Brighton Beach, One Down, Two to Go, The Personals, Pink Motel, The Pirates of Penzance, The Prey, Poltergeist, Pink Floyd-The Wall, Private Eyes, Psycho II, The Pursuit of D.B. Cooper and Quest for Fire.
  - Ratings Forms R-T, (1976, 1980-1982) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    With: Reds, Ragtime, The Raven, Rest In Peace, Revenge of the Shogun Women, Roommates, Roots of Evil, The Scaremaker, Secret Fantasy, Secret of NIMH, The Sender, Seven Beauties, Seven Sisters, Six Pack, Sharky's Machine, Six Weeks, Smithereens, The Soldier, Sorceress, Spetters, Spring Fever, Star Trek II: The Wrath of Khan, Stardust Memories, The Steel-Fisted Dragon, Still of the Night, Stir Crazy, The Sting II, Street Music, Super Power, Swedish Girls in Hamburg, Table for Five, Tempest, Tender Mercies, Tex, Threshold, Tijuana, Time Rider, Things Are Tough All Over, Time Bandits, Time Walker, Tootsie, The Toy, Trail of the Pink Panther, La Traviata, Treasure of the Four Crowns, Trick or Treat, Tron, Twilight Time and 2000 Year Old Man.
  - Ratings Forms U, V, W, X, (1981-1982) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    With: Up in Coming, The Verdict,Veronika Voss, Victor/Victoria, Videodrome, Virus, Waltz Across Texas, Wasn't That a Time, White Dog, The White Lions, Years of Living Dangerously, Yes, Giorgio, Yol and Young Doctors in Love.
- Richard Heffner, 1977-1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  There is no specific arrangement to the series.
  The series comprises one folder of photocopied memorandum, correspondence, and notes to and from Richard Heffner, Chairman of the Classification Ratings Administration. Some memorandum appear to be observations from film raters outlining how they evaluate films. Of note is a statement by Heffner for the Subcommittee on Special and Small Business Problems of the Committee on Small Business of the United States House of Representatives.
- Motion Picture Rating System Printed Material, 1977, 1982, early 1990s, undated
  The series consists of printed ephemera and publications including a Motion Picture Rating Directory, Motion Picture Rating System by Jack Valenti, and Rules and Regulations of the Classification Rating Administration, among others.
  The series is arranged alphabetically by titles.
  - Censorship excerpts pertaining to Germany, Norway, Republic of South Africa, Sweden, United Kingdom, United States, Zimbabwe, (undated) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Classification and Rating Administration Annual Reports 1968-198[0], (undated) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Everything You Always Wanted to Know About the Movie Rating System Compliments of AMC Theatres brochure, (undated) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - The Motion Picture Code and Rating Program: A System of Self-Regulation pamphlet, (undated) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Motion Picture Rating Directory published by CARA, (1982 Oct 1) (Box 1, Folder 14-15)
    General
    Cover removed for preservation purposes.
  - The Movie Rating System: How it Began, Its Purpose, How it Works, The Public Reaction by Jack Valenti (2 copies), (undated) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - R Edited to Avoid An X lists (2 copies), (undated) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Rating Symbols and Official Sizes for Newspapers circular (2 copies), (undated) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Rules and Regulations of the Classification and Rating Administration, (1977 Aug) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - The Voluntary Movie Rating System: How it Began, Its Purpose, The Public Reaction booklets, (1991, 1994) (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Memos and Communications, 1979, 1980-1983, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  The series comprises one folder of photocopied interoffice memos and general communications pertaining to the classification and ratings of motion pictures.
- Clippings and Articles, 1975,1980-1983, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 20-26)
  The series consists of assorted clippings from newspapers, magazines, and/or journals related to motion picture ratings and the ratings system. The bulk of the materials are photocopies. Publications include The Hollywood Reporter, Los Angeles Times, New York Times, TV Guide, and Variety. Also included is an article written by Sigler titled, Building an Intellectual Freedom Policy for Video Collections.
  - Building An Intellectual Freedom Policy for Video Collections by Ronald F. Sigler, (1991 Nov 1) (Box 1, Folder 22)
    From the publication, Video Rating Guide for Libraries (Vol. 2, No. 1, 1991).
  - Cable related clippings from Hollywood Reporter and Variety, (1981-1982) (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Magazine and Journal clippings, (1980-1983) (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Newspaper clippings (3 folders), (1975,1980s and 1990s) (Box 1, Folder 25-27)
- Accession LSC-2292-2015-09 backlog material, LSC-2292-2015-09; 0.25 linear feet (1 half doc box) (Box 2)